If you don't use cloth, you're falling
behind because Enthropic just released
Sonet 4.5, Cloth Code 2.0, a new agent
SDK, browser use, and so much more. My
name is David Andre, and I'm the founder
of Vector.ai. Over the last 3 years,
I've spent hundreds of hours building
software with AI. And in this video,
we'll look at the new cloth updates, how
sonet 4.5 compares to GPD5, and how you
can build anything with it. So, Cloth is
having its own CHBD moment, and that's
because Enthropic just released Sonnet
4.5, which in many ways is the best
model in the world. It's exactly five
times cheaper than Opus 4.1, which was
already incredible, while beating it on
nearly every benchmark. Now, since Sonet
4.5 released, I've spent more than 20
hours testing it, building with it, and
comparing it to other cuttingedge
models. And I must say, this model is
different. For example, on the famous
SWEBench verified benchmark for software
engineering, it's better than everything
else in the world right now. Both
without reasoning and with reasoning
enabled. Oh yeah, and if that wasn't
enough, Enthropic also dropped cloth
code 2.0 with several major upgrades
such as checkpoints, which is a way to
go back and access a previous state of
the conversation. A new revamped
terminal interface with a cool mascot,
context editing, ID extension. There is
a lot. Okay, cloth code has improved
massively and that's because this is by
far the biggest CL code update ever and
you'll see why I think that in a bit.
All right, so when I say that cloth is
becoming better than CHBT, let me show
you what I mean. So here I have prepared
a prompt for a simple app, create a
JavaScript app where text explodes into
particles that respond to mouse movement
with options for different physics like
magnetism, propulsion, or orbital
motion. And you can see that Sonet 4.5
is already way way faster than Opus 4.1.
And that's because it's a smaller model
while at the same time being a more
powerful intelligent model. And boom,
just like that, in a matter of 20
seconds, we have our app finished. So,
let's open this up and let me see. This
is insane. All right, let's try a
repulsion. This is incredible. And this
was done in a single prompt, one shot,
no corrections, no errors. It's safe to
say this model is amazing at
programming. Now, I think you might
start to understand what I mean by
saying cloth is underrated. Also, you
can now create and edit sheets.
documents, slides, and PDFs directly
inside of Cloud AI. It's funny because
most people are still not using Cloud.
They're using CIGPD. But even those that
are using Cloud, the vast majority of
them have no idea that these features
and connectors even exist, let alone how
to use them. So, let me show you how to
set this up because it's actually much
simpler and easier than you think. All
right, so let's jump back into Cloud.
Just create a new chat and then click on
this settings button right here. This
will open up different search options,
right? such as extended thinking
definitely have this enabled but then
also we can connect Google Drive, Gmail
and calendar. And as you can see I have
Google Drive already enabled. If you
don't have anything connected just
choose one of them, click on connect. Go
through the steps. Super easy. Takes
like 20 seconds. Once you do that,
reload the site and then you should be
able to see Google Drive or Gmail
calendar connected. Just toggle it on.
And then let me show you how powerful
this is. You can send a prompt something
like this. Which video ideas is my team
working on? List out the five most
recent Google Docs. Right? And there we
Oh, the search has finished and we have
five Google Docs that it pulled up and
yeah, those are actually the five most
recent video ideas that we worked on and
this one is the video you're watching
right now. Now, Cloth also became much
much better at VIP coding. In fact, this
might be VIP coding 2.0 because
Enthropic just released Cloth imagine
and this is a completely new way of
building software. The app you describe
is generated on the go. So you don't
need to wait for hundreds of lines of
code to be written and then hope that
they compile without any errors. No,
that's VIP coding 1.0. This clude
imagine works on pre-built components.
So it's basically like its own operating
system in a way where it can generate
custom UI in real time. So to test it
out, go to claw.ai/imagine.
Not everybody has access, so keep that
in mind. All right, so let's give it a
shot. Click on let's go and you can see
basically like a mini operating system
gets loaded. We can move stuff around.
So, let me show you one of these
presets. And you chat with cloth and it
generates stuff, but it generates it
procedurally. It's not like it has to
write a thousand line program. See, like
it's generating it one by one. It's like
adding a component and you can already
interact with the other ones. As you
explore the app, it's built in real
time. This is completely different than
any other vibe coding tool. So, like
let's see like for example this guild
quest, right? I click on that and clone
begins generating the UI for that. And
as I'm trying to see like what I like,
what interests me, it goes with that
direction. It's like completely
different level of creative exploration.
A map with 10 points of hidden
treasures. Now, the obvious downside of
this is that it's not reproducible
software and it's basically generating
tokens for everything, even stuff that
should just be a few lines of Python.
So, you can see the tools that it's
calling. Window new creates a new
window. And now it's drawing some SVG
components creating a map based on my
description. This is very very cool. Now
if you really want to understand cloth
4.5 set you have to learn about this new
concept of context anxiety. So this is a
new term coined by the article from
cognition AI the creators of Devon where
they discuss their experience with sonet
4.5 because they were granted early
access. Now this model cla 4.5 sonnet is
the first model in the history of AI
that is actually aware of its context
window. So what that means it knows how
many tokens it used up and how much is
left and this completely changes how it
behaves. So for example, as it gets
closer to its context limit, it starts
to summarize its progress, which is good
to save up some tokens, but also it
starts to develop this context anxiety,
which is basically a tendency to rush
tasks into completion. If it thinks
like, oh no, I only have 15% of the
context window left. It doesn't do
proper job. Instead, it tries to kind of
pack it up quickly and finish whatever
it's doing, even if that means taking
some shortcuts. Now, here's a
visualization of how the context editing
works. So before context editing you
have some tokens from tool use from the
tool results maybe some chatting
conversation another tool use stuff like
that. This is what the context window
might look like. After context editing
it compacts the oldest one. Here is the
current state. This is your last message
on the right and this is the oldest
stuff in the conversation. Right? So
whatever you send at the very beginning
is probably the least relevant. So it's
compacted into the true essentials. And
then as you keep progressing towards
your latest messages, you can see that
there's more available context because
the oldest parts of the conversations
have been compressed. Now, as if all of
that wasn't enough, there is another
major release and that is computer use
which might be one of the most exciting
parts actually because AI agents are
starting to use our browsers. So,
Enthropic also released a browser
extension, official cloud browser
extension, which basically lets clo
control your browser, you know, no big
deal. Another massive update that most
people aren't paying attention of and
this is a major hit to companies like
Perplexity who are building products
like Comet or DIA browser because these
AI powered browsers have several massive
issues such as privacy. Right? I was
using Comet for a solid like 2 3 weeks
until I did some deep research into how
much data it collects on you. And this
is basically spyware. It's building
digital profiles of every single click,
every single search, every single thing
you hover over, every single website you
visit, even like your mouse patterns,
right? And it's trying to build a
digital avatar so that then it can run
ads. The issue is me and you, we want to
be on the cutting edge. And this is
exactly where the cloth extension comes
into place. You can still use privacy
first browsers like Brave and use AI
agents with browser use on top of that
without selling your data and selling
your soul. So, let me show you what this
cloth browser extension can actually do.
Now, this is still a pilot program, and
what that means is that they only give
access to 1,000 users with the Max plan.
Now, luckily, I am one of those 10,000
people, so I can access the extension,
right? So, if you want to try, if you're
in those 10,000 people, just go to
cloth.ai/chrome
and see if you can install the
extension. If you can, you're going to
get redirected to this website where you
can try a demo of how the computer use
agent works. So, again, it's in the top
right. open it up and you'll be required
to log in to your Claude account. Okay,
so just click on authorize and then
let's click on this plus icon which
presends this prompt. It's kind of small
and as you can see this orange outline
means that Claude is taking control of
this browser window. So it's asking me
for a permission to read the page
content. So I'm going to allow this
action. So then it's taking a screenshot
of this page. Okay. So it can see the
email inbox with several emails I can
identify and it's completing this demo.
So this is a challenge, right? So you
can see how it operates, how it can read
the website, how it can take actions.
It's asking for permission again. And we
can actually click on always allow
actions on this side. So let's allow
that. And let's watch cloth take
control. Like my my hands are off the
keyboard, right? I'm not doing anything.
Boom. There it is. So it's clicking
archive. It's archiving one of the
emails. Took a screenshot again. Then it
read the page. So it read the HTML DOM
to find the exact buttons. And then it
found refct button. And it clicked the
button. And we can see that it's
managing this, you know, email inbox
demo. Now, what's even better than a
demo of email inbox is if it can
actually manage your real inbox. So,
let's give it a shot. Let's open up the
extension. You can see that there's
something predefined for Gmail such as
unsubscribe from promotional email,
archive non-important emails, drive
response for emails. So, let me do
something custom. I'm going to switch it
to act without asking, which kind of
gives this warning mode. You can see
this yellow lines. I'm going to say
archive all the declined emails about
people declining Google Meet calls. Do
not change anything else, you know, just
to be sure because this is still a pilot
program. It's basically earlier than a
beta version, right? So, I don't want it
to start messing around sending emails
from my actual email inbox or archiving
important stuff. So, now it's uh
searching for declined. Okay, it's
actually working pretty fast. It's
impressive. So now it filtered to emails
where people declined Google Meet calls.
Now it's selecting all of them. Whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Maybe not all of
them, you know. Maybe not all of them.
So I stopped it. I'm going to say maybe
not all. Just archive the latest five.
Yeah, I'm going to do smiley face to
kind of encourage it. You know, good
that I noticed that. Okay, it's going
again. Nothing is selected now. Nice.
Now it's going one by one. So as you can
see, it's still needs a bit of the
instruction, but it can actually do all
the actions. It's not struggling with
clicking buttons or with understanding.
It completely knows what you want it to
do. You just need to do a little bit of
handholding and be very clear in your
prompts and it will do exactly what you
want. And it skipped those emails that
didn't fit the criteria. Wow, this is
pretty crazy. It's trying to give it a
label, which is not the right way to do
it. There is a archive button. Okay. Oh,
it noticed that I actually opened label
button. Let me close this. Pressed
escape to close it. Let's see if it can
find the archive button correctly. It
found the archive button. And there it
is. Five conversations were archived.
All done. Now again, if you are a low IQ
person, you might think, "Okay, David,
but you had to interfere. You had to be
very specific in your prompts." Guys,
this is still early days. Use a bit of
your imagination and see where this will
be 6 months from now, 12 months from
now, where these AI agents will be able
to navigate every single website.
Basically, better than the average
knowledge worker at a company with
remarkable consistency and reliability.
Right now, what you just saw is the
level one of this extension. The second
level is actually this super small
settings button in the top right. And
when you open that, you click and click
on shortcuts. This is why you should
subscribe to this channel because I
actually show you all of this hidden
stuff that nobody else covers, right? So
if you aren't subscribed, go below,
click the subscribe button. It's
completely free and you will not miss
the cutting edge AI updates. So here you
can click on create shortcut and
basically this is like a mini
automation. This is a slash command. You
could say archive useless emails and
then the prompt would be open Gmail and
look through the latest unread messages
and anything that's obviously useless or
low leverage just archive it right away
and obviously you should ideally spend
more time on the prompt but this will do
for now and then start from you can give
it the starting URL so I can just paste
in Gmail boom maybe without the search
and then the beauty here is that you can
run it on a schedule so let's say you do
daily 9:00 a.m. and it will just manage
your email inbox every day and out.
Whatever you want it to do, you can now
automate it to run daily or weekly,
monthly, annually, maybe like check for
birthdays or something. Like there's a
lot, right? You can you can get creative
and you can figure out how this browser
use agent could be useful. But again,
this is just scratching the surface of
what it can do. And honestly, this will
probably require its whole video to
explore this fully. So, if you want me
to make a full dedicated video on the
cloth chrome extension, comment below.
And if I see a lot of people commenting,
maybe I'll consider making another video
on this. Now, if you're a developer, you
will be very interested in this because
Entropic is giving us a agent SDK. And
what that means is the behind the scenes
of cloud code. So, this is a collection
of tools that helps developers build AI
agents. And not only that, it actually
helps you build AI agents the same way
they are building CL code. So, it's the
same infrastructure that powers cloud
code, which is very, very nice. You
know, Infropic is releasing a lot of
these secrets. Now, it's not fully open
source, but the fact that you can still
use the same tools and frameworks that
work behind the scenes of what makes CL
code great, it's very nice. So, let me
give you a quick overview of this
powerful framework, which again, most
content creators ignored for some
reason. Maybe they're just scared of
programming. I don't know. First part is
the AI agents manual. They found that
giving clude access to computer aka
computer use unlocks the ability to
build way more efficient agents, right?
So, here are some examples on the right.
finance, personal assistant agents,
customer support, no matter what you
want to build, giving it access to the
right tools and the right environments
is absolutely key. Now, behind the
scenes, cloud code operates in a
feedback loop. So, it gathers context,
takes an action, verifies the work that
you know the action actually did what
you want it to do, and then it repeats.
And this is basically the four-step loop
that keeps running behind the scenes in
when you're using cloud code, when
you're chatting with it. And Enthropic
didn't hold back. They give us specific
suggestions on how this SDK can improve
each one of these steps. So step one is
gathering context. When developing an
agent, it needs to be able to fetch and
update its own context, right? Because
if it doesn't have enough information,
even if it's using a 300 IQ AGI model,
if it doesn't have the right info, if it
doesn't have the context of how you want
it to do the task, it will not be able
to do the task. Now, the SDK organizes
information using folders and files,
making it easy for the agent to find
what it needs. And if you actually work
with cloud code, you'll find that the
best way to manage context is actually
saving the imported stuff externally
right into markdown files, text files,
documentation, visual graphs, not just
only relying on the context window. And
when reading context, especially when
it's large files, it only loads the
relevant parts instead of everything at
once. So imagine if you have a very long
file, you know, five 500 lines of code,
1,000 lines. Ideally, you know, you
would have a more modular codebase, but
let's be honest, sometimes it happens to
all of us where we have super long
files. Well, your first instinct, and I
made this mistake in the past myself,
would be to load the entire file into
cloud code. The issue with that is
context overload, right? It's just too
much stuff at once and most of it is not
relevant. A much better approach, and if
you actually watch how cloud code works,
you'll see that it does this, is only
loading the relevant parts, right? So
when there's a bug on line 75, instead
of reading all 400 lines of the file, it
reads maybe the 20 lines before and 20
lines after so that it tries to figure
out why the back is happening. And it
only reads more lines of code if it
didn't get enough context from those
nearby lines. So it's much more
intelligent system of managing context.
It also automatically summarizes past
conversations to keep important
information available without running
out of space. And we've seen a
visualization of that earlier. Step
number two is taking action. This is all
about tools, right? AI agents use tools
to take actions which could be like a
single function or a series of functions
to do a specific thing. And this
absolutely is essential for completing
tasks because if you just have AI agent
running locally on your machine with no
tools, no APIs, it cannot do anything
even if it's the most powerful model in
existence. Now these tools should be
focused. You shouldn't give it random
tools because those are also
distractions. They should be tools
designed to what you want the agent to
do. So if it's like a email responding
agent, it should be open Gmail, read
email, write a draft email, anything
related to managing your email, right?
You shouldn't be giving it the
calculator tool. You shouldn't be giving
it, I don't know, Python backend
debugging tool. It's useless. If it's an
email management agent that you're
building, give it tools to manage email.
Step number three is verifying the work.
Right? This is a a step that most people
skip because it's not sexy. It's kind of
boring. But if you want to build
reliable agents that actually work in
production, it is absolutely essential.
With the agent SDK, you can add checks
to make sure things are correct, right?
So if it writes some code, run a test.
If it writes an email, take a
screenshot, make sure the email is
actually there. Same thing for visual
task like building front end HTML. It
can take screenshots. It can check its
work. It can read the DOM. There is a
lot of different verifying steps it can
do to make sure that the action or let's
say it's you you're working with
database, right? And you told it to
write an entry into the DB before
continuing. it can just do another tool
call but this time doing a read query
checking if the table has been modified
and if the new row was added to the
database. Now the agent performing these
checks is absolutely the difference
between reliable consistent agents that
can be trusted and deployed into real
businesses to automate important work
and between AI agents that are just like
what you see on YouTube lot of these
creators you know vibe code something
but no real company would ever use that
and this is the difference you know
using serious frameworks using serious
testing unit tests verification
monitoring telemetry all of this stuff
that you only learn when you go deep you
know when you spend spend hundreds of
hours if not thousands of hours building
software. This is not what you learn
with a quick VIP coding demo from a
5minute tutorial. And I suspect this is
the reason why most people completely
missed the agent SDK release and why
they don't realize the implications of
this. So here is the plan. Next, I'll
show you the new Cloud Code 2.0 and how
it compares to Codex with the new GPD5
Codex High model from OpenAI. We'll also
go over the strengths and weaknesses of
the new Solid 4.5 model, plus my own
lessons and observations from testing it
non-stop for four straight days. And
I'll show you how you can use this new
LLM to build great software. So, let's
get started. All right. So, open up your
code editor of choice. Doesn't matter
which IDE you use. So, I use cursor also
use code or you can use wind surf.
Doesn't matter. Just open up an empty
folder. The reason why it doesn't matter
is because you can use cloth code in the
terminal. Now, this is Codex. We don't
we don't want to be using Codex. We want
to be using the terminal and type cloth,
right? If you don't have cloth code
installed, what are you doing? Go ahead
and install it. Um, I made dozens of
videos on it because it's amazing. But
yeah, this is the terminal version,
right? So, you're probably familiar with
this if you watch my channel. And you
can see that there is new UI. So, we
have this mascot, you know, the crab.
And uh we can see that we're using Sonet
4.5, the new model. You can see that
we're on the cloth code 2.0 version and
we have some tips. But other than that,
this is the familiar terminal interface,
but there is a second way to use cloth
code now. And that is the extension. So
if you go to tensions, boom, and it's
named cloth code for VS Code. Literally
type in that cloth code for VS Code from
Enthropic. I don't know why it has
reviews. So that's kind of I
think you need a Microsoft account. Open
VFX registry. Yeah, you need some crazy
account for this. Uh, I don't know.
People are hating on it for no reason.
Download this. Okay, set this up. You'll
see this button right here. When you
click this, it opens up the extension.
Okay, and this is what it looks like.
It's basically the same capability but
with a different UI. So, here you can do
shift enter, which is great because uh
in the terminal, shift enter doesn't
work. It just sends the message. Never
mind, it works now. Maybe I'm just
crazy, but literally this didn't work
for forever. So, now it works again.
Amazing. Uh, anyways, this is just a
different UI, right? So, here you can
paste an images easier. You can chat
with it. It's another way of using cloud
code. Now, I'm going to just tell you
the secret right away. I'm going to cut
the The way to use it is with
Codex. So, if someone says like, "Oh,
David, is it better than Codex or should
I use Cloudcore or Codex?" The answer is
both. They both have completely
different strengths. Okay? There's not a
single answer. Like, if you just want a
single answer like I don't know, just
like these people like, "Oh, what's the
secret? What's the one thing I can do to
get into shape?" What do you mean one
thing? You have to do like 10 different
things to be in great shape. Well,
what's the one thing I can do to build a
successful business? Be quiet. Okay. So,
you need to use all of the best tools at
your disposal, right? So, you can see
I'm using Cursor, which is the best AI
coding IDE. Inside of Cursor, I'm using
the two best coding agents, which is
Cloud Code and Codeex, right? And both
of them, I'm using them in the extension
and in the CLI. So, here we have the
cloth code. Let me kill it terminal.
Boom. Cloth. Right? This is how you use
it in the CLI which is command line
interface by the way which is the
terminal. Here's how you use codeex in
the CLI which you should do parameter-
search and then you need to allow it
right. So we have codex running gbt5
codex high which is the best model from
openai in the terminal. We have it
running in the extension which by the
way you install it the same open cordex
you install it exactly the same as any
other extension inside of VS code. So we
have Codex extension, we have Codex CLI,
we have cloud code CLI, cloth code
extension. This is literally how I work.
I'm using all of the best AI agents at
my disposal in a way where they are the
best. Right? So let's get practical. How
is clo code better than Codex? In what
ways would I use each of them? Right?
The the best way to explain it is that
cloth is nicer to work with. So if if I
say like uh create a new MD file named
vision MD, it will do exactly what you
want and it will do it quickly and it's
great explaining fakes and stuff like
that, right? The way to explain it is
like cloth code is a friendly co-orker
that you just love to see. You have a
great rapport with that co-orker. You
you are friends together. You love
chatting with him and it's a great
person. You know, it's a competent
co-orker. Codex is like the person who
sits in the room. He's kind of
antisocial. He he doesn't really like
anybody, doesn't talk to anybody, but
he's a genius programmer and everybody
knows it. This is the difference between
Codex and Cloud Code. Codex, especially
with GBD5 high selected, which is the
main model you should be using, is
really good. It's really insanely good.
I mean, it's crazy, right? Uh but
sometimes it just takes 10 minutes to do
the dumbest thing, something that clo
can do in one minute. Sometimes it has a
tendency to overthink, right? which is
good if you're doing a risky change. If
you're refactoring an essential part of
the codebase or do or fixing like a very
deep bug that you that you've been
battling it for many hours, you wanted
to prepare. You wanted to overprepare.
You wanted to do a lot of thinking to
spend 10, 15, 20 minutes preparing,
analyzing the codebase, using as many
tools as possible before it takes any
actions. you wanted to do that but
sometimes you want quick changes quick
safe changes of the front end some
tweaks this is where cloud codes come
into place now obviously you can select
GBT5 low which thinks less on average
you know lower reasoning effort but
still even on low and medium codec still
has a tendency to overthink so that's
why I'm saying like you really should
use both and you should know when to
deploy each model and when each AI agent
is struggle and where are his strengths
and weaknesses if you want to be at
cutting edge at the top 0.01% 01% of AI
programming because I want to make a
clear distinction right there is vibe
coders people who use tools like lovable
vzero replet uh bold who just like type
in stuff or like speak you know please
build me an app that looks like Shopify
but it's actually for uh Uber drivers
and it's like Airbnb clone and do not
make any mistakes those are vibe coders
right and there is nothing wrong
starting as a vibe coder but the goal of
every vibe coder should be to become a
real coder. This is the difference
between people who will be stuck and
endlessly in a mediocrity and people who
will achieve greatness. Is are you
afraid to get your hands dirty, right?
Will you forever be afraid of code or
will you learn the fundamentals so that
you can move 10 times faster? Because
let me get something straight.
Even though even though AI is becoming
great at programming, I'm spending one
to two hours per day studying software
architecture, software design,
programming, manually coding without AI.
Why? Because I recognize that if you
really want to get the most out of these
models, you have to get the most out of
this model, the OG neural network that's
in your head. If you haven't maximized,
which by the way, nobody has maximized.
If you haven't maximized your own skill
set and your own potential and your own
technical abilities. Oh my god, it's
actually building this slope. Okay,
that's crazy. I didn't wanted to build
that app. Let me just delete this.
Actually, I'm going to get started on
the app I want to build. So, before I go
on the other rant, let me just get it
started. So, I want to build a new
algorithm that came to me as I was
struggling to fall asleep. This
algorithm is for optimizing time to
first token for AI models, right? So we
will be using enthropic API with the new
cloth 4.5 sonet model and obviously
there's a certain delay between the
first token comes into place and this is
constant and consistent for everybody
that uses the enforopic API. However, I
had an idea how to build a chat
application that actually has a faster
time to first token and that is going to
be thanks to preloading. So we're going
to be looking at how the user is typing
inputs. Right? So what I need you to do
is build a very simple front end. Choose
the simplest text stack possible, right?
Just Python back end and JavaScript
front end. Let's keep it super simple.
And it's going to be a clean, minimal
chat application powered by anthropic
API. And the main differentiator with
the this algorithm for optimizing time
to first token is that we're going to be
paying attention to the typing patterns
of the user. And if the user stops
typing for more than 700 milliseconds or
longer, we're going to silently send the
message on the back end to the enthropic
API. So that if the user then actually
sends the message without adding any
extra characters, we would have already
began processing that request and
therefore we can cut down the perceived
time to first token versus if we
actually waited for the user to press
enter. Now it's important that if the
user continues typing, we abort or
abandon that previous API call and we
repeat the process again looking at the
cadence of his inputs and the delays
between these characters. I just gave
you a lot of, you know, ideas, a lot of
direction for my vision for this
program. Your task is to organize these
thoughts into a clear plan into this
vision MD documentation file. Do not
write any code yet. just help me
organize my thoughts and help me plan
this out. Think harder, be concise. All
right, so I just spent a solid two,
three minutes speaking what I want to
build. And again, this is the difference
between noobs and beginners that build
absolute slope with AI and people who
can build real production applications
like me because I've built a startup
that is doing over $10,000 a month in
monthly recuring revenue and we have
over 65,000 people who've used it.
vector and it's running in production
and I'm using AI to build it. Yeah, it's
it's hundreds of thousands of lines of
code and it works and it's improving
every single day. And this is the
difference between people like me who
can build real software with it. And by
the way, I'm no I'm not like a you know
I I know that sounded super egotistical,
but I know I'm like level one out of 100
levels when it comes to building a
software company, right? That's why I'm
reading all these books and that's why
I'm learning like crazy because I
recognize that I know nothing. But still
I have been able to build and deploy a
real software application that is used
by tens of thousands of people versus
these vibe coders that build shitty
software complete slope that nobody
uses. Even they themselves don't use it
because they don't even describe what
they want to build. They don't take even
just two or three minutes to sit down
and really think through what are you
trying to build? What is the thing I'm
building? How should it work? How should
it feel? Is it a web application? Is it
a script? Is it a mobile app? Is it a
extension? Just put in some effort guys.
Put in some preparation. This alone will
make your apps and make your experience
with AI five times 10 times better.
Anyways, we have this markdown file and
we can see that it's now better
organized. We can see we have the core
key algorithm uh user experience flow
technical stack and um yeah another
thing I'm actually going to do we switch
to the browser again load up perplexity
and I'm going to do idea should be like
project whatever and I'm going to say
your task is to look up the enthropic
dogs necessary to build this chat
application idea give me detailed
step-by-step instructions of how to
implement this in Python in my back end.
So again, I'm using uh the best tools
available. So perplexity research is
very solid
to uh do the job. Right. All right. So
we have the DB research results. I'm
going to copy that and I'm going to
create a new file for this. I'm going to
do enthropic docs
because we don't want to redoing the
same web search over and over and this
is essential part of this app. So now
I'm going to say follow vision and
enthropic docs and actually build this
app env. And then here
I'm going to
add this information. The enthropic API
key is stored in the env file named as
enthropic API key. Okay. So that uh
because uh the coding agents usually
cannot access ENV files right you can
see this is blocked by get ignore and
cloud code cannot read it or cannot
change it for security reasons which is
good but we also need to give it like
that means we need to give it
instructions about how this is
structured right so I'm going to add
this later doesn't matter here you can
actually see the env that's kind of
crazy
but yeah we're going to launch this
launch code
get it started and this is just a very
first uh very rough version of what this
algorithm could look like for optimizing
time to first token and the difference
is that rather than this and pre-loading
websites is that uh there's way lower
cost right pre-loading a website doing
an API call is kind of expensive but I
don't know I was I thought about this
and I think something like this will
exist maybe in an expensive you know
paid application only because for free
users this is not feasible at all and
maybe only for certain models maybe
Gemini free will be very cheap but yeah
it doesn't exist yet nobody yet invented
this and so I got the idea to build it
and I think this is a much cooler
project than just yet another vibe coded
website that's just an MVP of some front
end right this is a novel algorithm that
as I said I got the idea to build it as
I was falling asleep so it's solving a
real problem which is reducing time to
first token aka making your experience
in a chatbased application faster,
smoother, more pleasant. So, we can
already see how close code works here.
And again, we're using the extension
here. Uh we have Codex on the side.
We're not using it yet. What I should
have done and what I would have done if
I was working see like it's much easier
to build from scratch, right? Because
then you really can use the power of AI
and you can execute 50 times faster. If
I was building a feature for vectal my
startup, I would first create a plan and
I can actually feel free to screenshot
it and steal it. But basically what I do
is I send this and I paste in the plan.
So I asked both the models, both codecs
and cloud code to analyze all the
relevant files and create a simple
step-by-step plan for how to best
implement this feature, this change,
this refactor, whatever I'm doing. I get
both of them to implement a plan and
then using this prompt I insert it into
in between these XML tags and I get the
other model to rate the plan of the
other model and almost always they agree
that the codeex created plan is better.
I would say probably 90% of scenarios. I
mean to be honest if I could choose
right because I'm using both because
both do exist but if I could choose wow
it's already finished. Yeah, this more
or less great. It's very fast. But to be
honest, if I could only choose to have
access to one tool, it would be Codex.
Even though it's not as good to work
with, even though it's not as polished
as the plot code interface,
it is a more powerful model. GPD5 Codex
High is the best model for coding right
now in the world. It makes way less
errors. It uh designs a simpler
solution. It puts in more work, more
reasoning, more preparation, but it's
not as pleasant to work with. It uses
complex language. It doesn't explain
concepts well. It doesn't format its
answers in a re readable way. It often
overthinks simple changes that could be
like 5 seconds and it takes like minutes
analyzing everything. Overthinking.
It's not as pleasant to work with, but
it is more powerful. No questions asked.
So, let's see. Uh, we have the app
finished, I guess. What do we need to
do? Start it. How do I start it? Ping
heart and string short. In the meantime,
we'll go to the browser. We need to load
up anthropic console. All right, let's
log in. Okay, next up, go to the top
right. Click on create key. I'm going to
go with effect AI and I'm going to do a
test video.
Boom. Copy key. Do not share your API
keys with anybody. Treat them as
passwords. I'm going to delete my key
before uploading this video. Okay. So,
I'm going to paste it into ENV file. I'm
going to save it and then let's see what
needs to happen.
We have the ENV. Okay. We need to
install requirements. So, let me do
that. Condv list
activate testing
the pip install requirements txt
clear. And then what do we need to do?
Python m server. This is Python server.
Python server. Pro tip. If you're using
the terminal, you can just press tab,
right? So, I type in SE and it already
knows I'm want to go server. So, you
don't need to finish the whole thing.
Just press tab inside of a terminal.
It's actually a very OP thing to do.
Okay. So, we have an error. So, I'm
going to screenshot it. I'm going to
send it back. I'm going to say the app
does not start. Error XML tax. Paste in
the terminal output. Error.
think harder and implement a clean and
minimal
fix.
And then I'm going to use codex new
chat. What does it want to do? Well,
okay, whatever. So, we have this. I'm
going to say test
send.
Doesn't send. Oh, yeah. I was accessing
the websocket. That's a lame mistake.
However, wait, why is the websocket
disconnected? Maybe to restart it. I
cannot
send a message now. Error. Boom.
Error. Investigate this and output a
concise report. Do not make any changes
yet. Just answer in short. Okay. And
then I'm going to run the same thing
into codex. And look how much work codex
will do. This just answered instantly
which maybe it's correct, maybe it's not
correct. Right? Sometimes it is good to
have a fast answer, but
if you want to build serious software,
this is very bad practice. Close code
just runs rushes into assumptions. It
jumps to conclusions, makes assumptions
way too fast. It's not good. One thing I
do want to show you though is uh when
you do terminal plot, there's a new
feature /re where you can restore the
composition to previous point. The
problem is that you've seen a lot of
people talk about this checkpoints.
First of all, there's two issues with
this. It was always accessible just by
pressing escape, right? So, you could
have pressed escape twice and go to the
past previous conversations. This was
always a feature. So, all the
influencers talking about this like this
is a new thing. It's not a new thing.
Second of all, learn how to use git.
Okay? Just you can ask teach me how to
use git. What are the fundamentals of
using git to build a startup? What are
the essential commands I need to know?
explain what g is and how to use it. Use
the AI to teach you. This is the best
thing about cloud code and about this
model in particular sonet 4.5. As I
said, it's much better at writing. So
I'm going to say implement a clean and
minimal fix. Both of them basically
agree that uh it's a websocket 13 thing.
The biggest thing, the best decision you
can do is using AI to upscale yourself
and clot based models. All of them are
much better at teaching and explaining
than GPD models. Like you'll see the way
Codex types is just um it's not I mean
again it's it's fine tuned for code,
right? It's GPD5 codex. It's not meant
to be a educational conversational
model. On the other hand, cloud models
are amazing at learning stuff. And this
is how you should use it. When you have
a bad error, you should reduce technical
debt by trying to understand it yourself
rather than trying to instantly ask the
AI to fix it. Problem with Codex is that
it doesn't do a good job explaining it.
It just doesn't write in a in a clean
way, in an explanatory conversational
way. L code, on the other hand, is
excellent at formatting, at explaining,
simplifying, summarizing.
It's still a great coding model, don't
get me wrong, and for certain things, I
certainly prefer it. like when I know
exactly what to do and it's a safe
targeted change, working with cloud code
is much better. But if I'm doing
something new, something risky, some big
refactor, some serious bug, I'm going to
definitely trust Codex because it just
does way more preparation.
That is the truth. But again, the best
thing is using both and then copying the
plan one of them gives you, feeding it
to the other one and asking which plan
is better and why. And most of the times
both of the models will agree and most
of the times they will agree that the
correct plan is better. So yeah, this is
my current setup and this is what I'm
using for four, five, six, seven,
sometimes eight, sometimes more hours a
day uh to build my startup and to build
all kinds of software and u yeah this is
a huge update to close code but don't
let those influencers tell you like it's
some crazy new thing because it's mostly
just polishes and you know switch to a
proper extension which you can use in uh
VS code and VS code forks like cursor
and witsurf A lot of people are still
scared of the terminal which is a big
mistake. If you spend couple of hours
learning how basic terminal commands and
how to use it and what it is, it's it's
not that scary. It's it's not that deep,
you know. Anyways, uh let's see. So, we
fixed this or I mean Codex fixed it.
Could have had Clco fixed it as well.
Let me clear this up. Restart the
server.
Uh we need to reinstall the
requirements. Okay. pip
install-requirements
txt. Again, I press tab to save time and
I'm going to do python server.py.
Reload this. We have the websocket
connected at the bottom now. That's
beautiful. So, I can say, "Hey, let's
see if it responds. We need to see."
Okay, so we are getting response from
Enthropic API. Who are you? Beautiful.
Now, obviously, this is a disgusting UI,
but uh I want to see if it does the
optimistic pre-loading. So, let me type
in something slowly.
uh help me understand the git.
Then it optimistic pre-loading started.
Boom. I didn't even have to. Okay. So,
it doesn't work perfectly as I want it
to work yet. I don't want it to like
display into the UI. I just want us to
have it and then only when I hit enter,
we would have it. Okay. So, I'm going to
describe that, but it's already really
good. Already uh achieves the purpose.
Okay. So, I fixed the issue. The next
problem is that I do not want to show
the results in the UI until
the user actually presses enter. Right?
So again, this should be a silent API
call. It should be optimistically
sending it and we should be like saving
the output
that we get from enthropic API when the
user stops typing for more than 700
millconds. However, we should not show
it in the chat until the user actually
hits enter. And then obviously since
it's a anthropic uh model typing ultra
think will cause it to spend more tokens
on reasoning. So that's another pro tip.
But uh you can see that uh we fixed like
two small things. We need a way to clear
the chat. So by by when that's happening
I'm going to use codex. Uh please update
the UI so that it's more minimalistic,
clean, and much better designed. This is
just way too basic and it's ugly as
So make the design look better.
and also add a button to clear the
conversation and start a completely new
chat from scratch. Analyze all of the
relevant files and implement these small
changes in a simple and clean way. Don't
overthink this. The fewer lines of code,
the better. And I'm going to change to
medium reasoning effort because I don't
want this to be running for 5 minutes.
Okay, so cloud code is fixing this.
It should do the optimistic call, but it
shouldn't display until I've actually
hit enter, right? until the user has hit
enter. Uh some people prefer Codex for
UI.
To be honest, I mostly use CL code for
UI. So I don't know people are bad
taste, I guess. But let's see. We say
what is git all about? Help me
understand git commit. Wait, optimistic
preload started. I'm not going to be
sending enter.
Reloading. Okay, pre-loading.
pre-loading. I'm going to hit enter.
Boom. Amazing.
Now it works how I want it. Okay. So,
basically, if you're typing, I mean,
obviously, this is going to burn through
cost. This is not a if you are on a
limited budget, you cannot build
solutions like this. However, do you see
the potential in this? We could change
the optimistic pre-loading to be
adaptive for each user, right? So it can
measure your average VPM words per
minute and then like once it notices a
slowdown or maybe we can make it like
based on a sentence, right? So if
there's like a dot word and a dot, it's
probably end of a sentence which
indicates that the user is probably
about to send the prompt and then we can
do the pre-loading like that.
There is a lot of ways we can optimize
this to be more reliable and
you know more cost effective but you can
already see the potential in this. I
mean I can already see the potential in
this. I don't know if you guys can see
it but yeah this something like this
will exist in the future because um you
know time to first token is just
essentially in a chatting application
chatbased AI application and what I just
built in a few prompts with sonet 4.5
already is a clear proof of concept
where like if you stop typing for a bit
and then you hit enter it uh already was
saving this on the back end the message
was already written
But if I continue typing, actually we
can test that. Help me understand
past API versus Django. Wait, I'm going
to have it start. Okay. And we'll say
which is better and why. This should
kill the previous request.
Yes, it didn't do
uh it didn't like preload the previous
request. It did a new one. That's good.
That's good. Okay, we need to restart
the UI, I guess.
Let's see. Reload. Oh, we have a nicer
new UI. List out 10 benefits of using
Git.
Yeah, this is a much cleaner UI. Hey,
maybe actually Codex is better at UI
than I thought. You know, going to have
to test it more. But yeah, this is uh
the current workflow. Codeex for risky
important actions. Cloud code for fast
work where you know you're doing
something specific. You it is safe. You
know what you're doing and you want to
move fast. Clo you want to iterate fast.
Close code is the way to go. And
especially now with 4.5 solid it's just
got a huge power up a huge speed up and
it's more cost efficient and you're not
going to be reaching limits fast as
fast. And really I want to stress it
again. The best way to use clot code is
for learning all the cloud models like
again you should use both right both
codeex and clot code but anything you're
doing whether it's fixing a bad bug or
implementing new feature or extending
your codebase refactoring
you should seek understanding even if
you're using AI agents to move faster
which guys I'm I'm like the the person
who benefited the most like there's few
people who built an entire startup from
scratch with AI with less previous
experience than me, okay? Whatever.
Like, I just benefited insanely from
using AI coding, okay? And my
productivist speed up was crazy. And I'm
still telling you that you should be
seeking to understand what it's doing as
much as possible. The goal of every vibe
coder should be to become a real coder.
There is a reason, again, I mean, I know
I mentioned this, I'm reading these
books. Why? Because I've hit the
limits of vibe coding. At a certain
point you have to realize I am the
limiting factor. You have to see like
okay the code base is a mess. It's not
modular at all. It's over complicated.
There's too much technical debt.
At that point you have to realize okay
LLMs are great following instructions.
But if you give them bad instructions
you're going to get bad results. So use
this to obscure yourself. This is the
big biggest differentiator. A lot of
people have this mindset of like oh I'm
just going to you know use AI models.
They're getting they're improving fast
right? models are improving fast. Ah,
it's there's no point learning this. In
five years, the models will be able to
do it. So, what what are you going to do
in five years? What are you going to do
in the next five years? Just sit around
and be mediocre and gain no advantage
over others. You have such amazing
opportunity to upskill yourself faster
than ever before.
If you want to truly get this to your
fullest potential, you should become a
software developer. You should learn the
art of software engineering and the
software development. And again, not
remembering pointless syntax, but
understanding the big picture concepts.
Again, if you don't even know how to use
git or the terminal, what are you doing?
Like, humble yourself and use the AI to
learn these complicated concepts, right?
Programming coding can be intimidating
if you're new to this. But you can use
the AI to explain it in a simple way,
right? So you could say, "Explain to me
the difference between object-oriented
programming and functional programming
using simple and plain English as if I
knew nothing about software
engineering." This is something that was
not possible before. Before you could
only use Google or YouTube and kind of
hope that someone explained it and it's
still very slow.
With AI, you can learn so much faster
than it was ever possible. And this
really is the differentiator. people who
will use AI to upskill themselves. I
don't care if it's marketing, sales, or
if it's programming. Whatever skill you
identify is going to take you to your
goals, you should be using AI to master
that skill and become the best in the
world. Obviously, if you're building
startups and if you're using AI to build
software, it is going to speed you up
without a doubt. And the models will
keep getting better and the tooling and
the AI agent support will get better.
All of that is true, but imagine if you
yourself also become better at the same
time and you have two exponentials
compounding on top of each other. Those
are the people who are going to
absolutely dominate, not the people who
just sit around. It's like, yeah,
there's no point of learning
programming. The models are going to be
better programmers than us. It's like,
all right, bro. If that's uh your
mindset, then feel free to feel free to
just sit around and do nothing. But I
would encourage you guys to use these
tools to build the future that you want
to see. A lot of people are building AI
slop. We see this from Meta and Open AI.
They're releasing short form AI videos.
Disgusting.
Disgusting. This is like societal
decline. Doesn't benefit society or
humanity at all. And I would encourage
anyone working those companies to leave
and build something meaningful. Build
the future you want to see. Use it to
solve diseases, to cure important
issues, to discover new science, invent
new technology, solve mathematical
problems, build great software.
That's how these models should be used,
not for slop, for endless entertainment,
like ruining society, you know, or like
same with Grock, you know, this like AI
girlfriends, disgusting guys. It's just
terrible. So, if you are someone who
wants to use these models to build
something great, if you're watching this
video, you're probably like an ambitious
individual that's hardworking, that is
above average IQ that pays attention to
current trends. Use that power to build
something meaningful. Build the future
you want to see, not a future full of AI
slope. Use these tools to learn how to
actually build great software. And if
you're going to become a ultra wealthy,
ultra successful individual, do it in a
way that you can look back when you're
80 and be proud of rather than building
these uh dopamine inducing AI slow
machines. So yeah, I I gave you the
blueprint. I showed you the path how to
do how to fix bugs, how to use these
tools is up to you to take action and
execute. So with that being said, thank
you for watching and have a wonderful
productive week.